hi everybody and welcome back to the
channel today we are going to look at
Ben and Jerry's Dublin mudslide so if
you want to see how we make our version
of it stick around and we'll show you
[Music]
first off what is Dublin mudslide we
can't get over here or if you can I've
never seen it in the shops
it is Irish cream ice cream with
chocolate chocolate chip cookies and
coffee fudge swirls
sounds quite similar to Haagen-Dazs
Irish Cream brownie but sounds pretty
nice they do use this Wayward spirit in
their new version their new release of
Dublin my slide again can't get it over
here I'm certainly not going to import a
bottle of
whatever it is I think it's way
obviously based alcohol but don't know
what it tastes like
it
is gonna be made with this instead Old
Faithful Bailey's Irish cream liqueur I
don't mind Bailey's it's okay it's a
little bit
cloying for me but if you're going to
make like a donut shot or something
with some Chambord it's really nice
so to make the ice cream base we're
going to start off with our milk in the
pan and then to that we're going to
start adding our sugars our dextrose and
our sucrose and we're going to warm that
milk up until it gets to around 50 to 55
degrees
at that point I find that the skim milk
powder starts to dissolve easier and
incorporate into your milk mixture once
it's all completely Incorporated you're
going to turn off the heat and then
slowly add in your cream we're using
whipping cream here and then finally add
in your Irish cream liqueur or Baileys
or whatever it is your fancy using and
then give it a nice quick stir and put
it in a container and put that in the
fridge to chill down take three or four
hours the next thing we're going to do
is we're going to prepare our coffee
fudge now here we're going to add our
milk and our golden syrup you can use
corn syrup if you want I find the golden
syrup adds a nice little extra bit of
something something to the fudge once
you've added that in turn the heat on
add in your sugar and then let that
Sugar dissolve before you add in your
cocoa powder and instant coffee now not
all instant coffee is created equally if
you've ever been to North America you
know what I mean get that completely
dissolved and then get it boiling a
really high rolling boil is what's
needed for this coffee fudge and what it
actually does is it starts to turn the
sugars into an invert sugar but we'll go
through that in another video anyway
once your fudge is really boiling you
can finally turn off the heat and add in
your physical chocolate that will bring
the temperature down keep stirring it
until it's nice and smooth take it off
the heat and put it in a container ready
for later
once your ice cream base is chilled
suitably take it out of the fridge give
it a final stir just to make sure
everything's mixed together well and
then pop it in your ice cream machine to
churn now whilst that's churning we're
going to take our cookies these are just
store-bought double chocolate chip
cookies you're going to cut them up into
a nice little one centimeter cubes or
whatever size pieces you want and just
put them aside because when the ice
cream is almost at completion in your
machine you're going to add in your
cookie pieces get them nicely
Incorporated take it out and start
loading at the tub now while you load up
the tub you're going to layer in your
coffee chocolate fudge and make sure
that there's plenty of that in there
before you close it up and put it in the
freezer for a few hours
foreign
[Music]
straight out the freezer now has been in
the freezer for a long time it's
probably I don't know a week maybe ish
and it's I can tell it's it's soft I've
loaded it up with the Baileys or Irish
cream liqueur
probably went a little bit too high on
the sugars but we'll
see but I'm really excited to just get
some of this scooped up and see what it
tastes like
[Music]
super soft to scoop
a very strong Irish Cream smell to it I
can smell it even I've got a cold
loads of fudge
I mean look at that fudge
and
the chocolate chocolate chip cookie
pieces why would they started saying
that why don't you just say double
chocolate chip
anyway let's
try some
and see what this is like
[Music]
that is good I mean I've always liked
Bailey's ice cream Haagen-Dazs used to
sell
just Bailey's
I mean that's going back
a while you used to get that when I was
12 13.
um
maybe it's still available it's not
available over in England but
it's surprisingly similar
to
the Haagen-Dazs Irish Cream brownie
surprisingly similar to that
and
I don't know if you can even see that
whether it's in Focus or not but
whatever
it surprisingly similar to that one you
know that one has brownie pieces and
normal chocolate fudge this one has
cookie pieces and coffee chocolate fudge
otherwise they're the same you can't
really go wrong with Bailey's and once
you add in those cookie pieces which add
a nice little change in texture and that
coffee chocolate fudge it's a really
nice combo I do think I've probably
either added too much alcohol or
slightly too much sugar so I'm going to
adjust the recipe Below in the
description so that you get something
that hardens just a little bit more than
this one does
I'm happy with it but I know a lot of
you like a slightly harder ice creams or
lower sugar ice cream so I'll drop that
recipe down just to suit the masses but
hopefully you enjoyed this one a nice
easy one if you use store-bought cookies
like I did I'm crap at making cookies at
home so I'm unlikely to make them for a
recipe like this but don't forget to
like And subscribe and we will see you
next time
[Music]